Guide to the John Taggart Archive ca. 1970-1974 MSS.025
Fales Library and Special Collections
John Taggart Archive
1970-1974
Fales Library and Special Collections
Taggart, John, 1942-
MSS.025
.25 Linear Feet in 1 half manuscript box.
The John Taggart Archive is a collection of correspondence John Taggart received as editor of Maps during 1970 to 1974. Collection highlights include correspondence from Carol Bergé, Paul Blackburn, Hayden Carruth, Robert Creeley, Guy Davenport, Gary Snyder, and Louis Zukofsky.
Provenance
The John Taggart Archive was acquired via purchases from Taggart between 1971-1975.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
[put Biographical or Historical here] Note
[concise information about the creator(s) of the described materials]
Scope and Content Note
The John Taggart Archive is a part of the Avant Garde Collection at Fales Library, New York University. The Fales Library is the primary special collections division of the NYU libraries, housing over 170,000 volumes of English and American literature from 1700 to the present. Strengths of the collection include the development of the English and American novel, with an emphasis on the Gothic and the Victorian novel. The Avant Garde Collection comprises printed materials, archives, and other materials related to the avant-garde writing from the 1960s and early 1970s. The collection was build during that period by curators, including Mel Edestein and Ted Grieder.
Arrangement
The John Taggart Archive is arranged in alphabetical order by correspondences and manuscripts.
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Small presses -- New York (State) -- New York.; Art, Modern |y 20th century |v Periodicals.; Literature, Experimental |x Periodicals.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; United States.; Manuscripts for publication.; American literature -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Authors, American -- 20th century.; New York (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; American fiction -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics); Downtown writers.; Zukofsky, Louis, 1904-1978; Carruth, Hayden, 1921-2008; Blackburn, Paul; Davenport, Guy; Bergé, Carol, 1928-; Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005; Snyder, Gary, 1930-
- Series I: Correspondence
  Scope and Contents note
  Series 1 contains one box of correspondence to John Taggert, editor of Maps. Noted correspondents include Carol Bergé, Paul Blackburn, Hayden Carruth, Robert Creeley, Guy Davenport, Gary Snyder, and Louis Zukofsky.
  - Allen, Donald Bergé, Carol Blackburn, Paul, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brakhage, Stan Bronk, William, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Butterick, George, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carruth, Hayden Creeley, Robert, 1970; 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Davenport, Guy, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Edson, Russell, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Eigner, Larry Elliott, George P., 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Goodman, Mitchell Greene, Jonathan, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Grossinger, Richard Harris, George Heller, Michael, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Justice, Donald Kenner, Hugh Krofsky, Frank, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meltzer, David Newlove, John Oppen, George, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pearson, Norman Holms Phelps, Donald Rothenberg, Jerome, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Silliman, Ronald Snyder, Gary Spann, Marcella Vas Dias, Robert, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Weil, James, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Weiss, Ted and Renée Whalen, Philip Zukofsky, Louis, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)